这是一个用户类。
Here's a user class.
我们有一个构造函数，我们有名字，
We have a constructor, and we've got first name,
姓氏，在那里写一个全名，很酷。
last name, makes a full name down there, cool.
做得好。
Job well done.
我们有一个用户，它可以工作。
We have a user and it works.
我们尝试了不同的方式。
We tried a different way.
我们有一个用户数据类型。
We have a user data type.
我们有全名。
And we have full name.
这次我们使用连接，同样的事情。
This time we're using joins, same thing.
但在那里，工作方式与之前完全相同。
But down there, works exactly the same as it did before.
这里有区别，我们实际上可以重命名
There's a difference here, we can actually rename
这个全名在这里我们加入第一个和最后一个加入空间吧？
this full name here where we join the first and last to join with space, right?
现在，让我们尝试用空格连接 firstName 和 lastName。
Now, let's try to join the firstName and the lastName with a space.
突然之间，出现了这些属性。
And all of the sudden, emerges these properties.
如果我们开始概括，如果我们开始尝试使用
If we start to generalize, if we start to try to work with
这些属性，我们最终注意到 joinWithSpace 在那里是关联的。
these properties, we end up noticing that joinWithSpace is associative down there.
我如何分组它们并不重要。
It doesn't matter how I group them.
因此，我可以随心所欲地加入，最终得到这些
Therefore, I can join as many as I want, and I end up with these
组成的角色，这很好，我没有全名。
roles of composition, which is nice I didn't have that with for full name.
事实上，在 joinWitSpaces 中，可重用的实用程序现在没有被埋没和
In fact in joinWitSpaces, reusable utility now that's not buried and
卡住并绑定到一个要一次又一次重写的对象。
stuck and tied to an object to be rewritten again and again.
或者你可以更进一步说 joinWithSpaces，
Or you can take it a step further and say joinWithSpaces,
我们将采取任何joinable。
we're going to take any joinable.
所以我们要编程到可连接的界面。
So we're going to program to the interface joinable.
然后我们将传入一个数组，它是可连接的。
And then we'll pass in an array, which is joinable.
但它可能是其他东西，可能是一棵树，
But it could be other things, could be a tree,
可以是具有键和值的对象。
could be objects with keys and values.
所以我们将传入一个joinable，然后我们再次得到joinWithSpaces。
So we'll pass in a joinable and there we get joinWithSpaces again.
这与封装是一回事。
And this is the same thing as encapsulation.
所以joinWithSpaces 唯一能做的就是join。
So the only thing joinWithSpaces can do is called join.
它什么都不知道。
It knows nothing else.
它得到了一个连接，它无法决定查看对象。
It gets a joinable it can't decide to look at the object.
如果你回想起我们之前的那个用户类，让我回到这里，
And if you think back to that user class where we had, let me go back up here,
我们拥有整个用户以及所有其他方法。
we have the entire user at our disposal and all the other methods.
我们这里有这个。
We have this in here.
所以我们可以做很多事情。
So we can do a lot of stuff.
但是在这里，实际上我们可以做一件事，我们可以调用 join。
But over here, there's literally one thing we can do, we can call join.
就是这样。
And that's it.
所以这真的只是让这个特别的论点。
So it's really just the argument that makes this special.
更进一步，如果我们有恒等函数，它需要一些 a 和
To take it a step further, if we have the identity function, it takes some a and
将其退回。
returns it back.
它无法使用该值做任何事情。
There's nothing it can do with that value.
它对此一无所知。
It knows nothing about it.
它不能调用任何方法。
It can't call any methods.
它对它无能为力。
It can't do anything to it.
这就是我们如何通过函数式编程获得封装。
And so this is how we get encapsulation with functional programming.
有人对此有任何疑问吗？
Does anybody have any questions on that one?
因为这是一个奇怪的概念。
Cuz it's a weird concept.
封装是抽象和
The encapsulation is the dual of abstraction and
这是它的抽象方面，你对它一无所知。
this is kind of the abstraction side of it is that you don't know anything about it.
所以我实际上无法触摸它。
So I can't actually touch it.
因此，我得到了有关它的信息。
So therefore I get information on it.
&gt;&gt; 该函数的价值是什么？
&gt;&gt; What's the value of that function?
&gt;&gt; 如果我们进入 Run dev。
&gt;&gt; If we jump into Run dev.
所以，让我们看看我是否有
So, let's see if I have
= 要求（&#39;类型&#39;）。
= require('types').
酷，让我们先说Either.of(2).fold。
Cool, let's first say Either.of(2).fold.
让我们继续制作身份。
Let's go ahead and make identity.
它需要一个 a，返回一个 a。
And it takes an a, returns an a.
我实际上可以通过说我有
I can actually fold out the value by saying I have
一个函数，它获取该值并将其吐回给您。
a function that takes that value and spits it back out at you.
而不是必须编写一个接受数字二和的处理程序
Instead of having to write a handler that takes the number two and
然后返回第二个，这和这个一样，对吧？
then returns the number two, that's the same as this, right?
我只能称之为身份。
I can just call identity.
这样会更派上用场
That will come in handy more and
在你的函数式编程生涯中更多，但是
more throughout your functional programming career, but
看到蝙蝠有点奇怪，但最终它是一个很好的实用程序。
it's it's a little weird to see off the bat but eventually it it's a good utility.
是啊，怎么了？
Yeah, what's up?
&gt;&gt; 公平地说，函数式编程中的很多东西都依赖于
&gt;&gt; Would it be fair to say that a lot of things in functional programming rely
在身份模式上，但我们作为程序员不会把
on the identity mode, but we're as programmers not gonna be putting
它的使用频率与我们使用的结构所使用的频率一样高？
it to use as frequently as it's used by the structures that we use?
&gt;&gt; 可以这么说。
&gt;&gt; That's fair to say.
我们实际上会看到在提供身份的单声道变压器中
We'll actually see that in mono transformers supplying the identity
恢复原始类型的转换器的函子。
functor to a transformer which recovers the original type.
这是一个很好的实用工具，它是从理论上建立起来的。
It's a great utility to have and it's founded in theory.
我们有包含 f 和 g 的组合，并且我们有一个恒等式。
We have composition which takes f and g, and we have an identity.
事实上，事实证明这是你需要定义的两件事
And actually, it turns out that those are the two things that you need to define
一个范畴，范畴论，它们是无孔不入的。
a category, and category theory and they're pervasive.
当我们谈论幺半群时，我们马上就会看到其中的一些内容。
And we'll see some of that in a minute here when we talk about monoids.
功能上的标识只需要进行价值转移。
Identity on functions just takes a value transfer.
让我们继续，好吧，所以我们想要高度泛化的函数。
Let's go to, okay, so we want highly generalized functions.
这不是硬性规定。
That's not a hard rule.
这只是一个很好的指导原则。
It's just a good guiding principle.
说我将继续抽象直到我编程到最
To say I'm just going to keep abstracting away until I'm programming to the most
最小的界面。
minimal interface.
然后我得到了最大的重用，我得到了信息隐藏。
Then I get the maximum reuse, and I get information hiding.
如果我在这里改变我的程序，它不会产生涟漪。
And if I change my program here there, it's not gonna ripple.
所以我们继续研究这些更高的高度泛化的函数
So we keep working on these higher highly generalized functions
直到我们达到一个很好的平衡。
until we hit a nice balance.